係。
啊，跟住阿Mr. White。
你做唔做啊？
入嚟啊！唔該曬。
早晨，歡迎各位啊！
鼻敏感啊！
誒，各位同事，就我哋咧呢個誒。
佢哋係邊個負責講啊？秘書長。
哦，好啊！誒，大家覺得有冇需要選副主席喎？
早上各位，啊，咁而家我哋不如先請誒。
哦，冇冇噉嘅需要係嘛？好，噉我哋不而家請誒有關嘅官員。
啊！呢個黃定光議員和議，陳振英議員接唔接受？接受，接受。O.K.，仲有冇其他提未？
幾好藉口咯，OK，啊，冇其他提名，OK，好，我宣佈陳振宇議員當選，OK。
咁按照議程咧，而家誒，不如先由政府當局向大家各位委員咧簡介下呢個條例啦，好唔好啊？噉啊，由邊位介紹？阿郭助理秘書長係咪？唔該曬。
係誒，多謝主席。咁誒，我我哋誒首先會簡介一下關於金融機誒機構處置條例誒生效公告同埋受保障安排嗰個嗰個內容。
金融機構豁護處置機制受保障安排規例同埋二零一七年金融機構處置機制條例生效日期公告嘅小組委員會咧，第一次會議好。噉我哋咧就選個主席先，有冇提名？陳建波議員。提名阿陳。陳正怡。陳振英議員。好。
嘅時候咧，可以誒處置佢哋嘅。
噉樣處理呢一類巨蟹系統重要性嘅金融機構。
Thank you, Mr. Wright. We would like to give us some background about this bill, right? Thank you, Mr. Koay Yatch.
誒受保障安排規例嘅內容咧，我我請誒金管嘅金管局嘅同事簡介一下。
金融穩定理事會主要元素裏邊嘅國際標準，咁誒，以下落嚟關於嗰個誒。
做人因應誒嗰個金融危機咧，就要求當時嘅金融穩定理事會去諗一諗，究竟點樣去應付誒金融機構大到不能倒嘅現象。
To help the discussion, a clearing and settlement system arrangement means an arrangement governed by the rules and directions relating to participation in the clearing and settlement of transactions within the financial market infrastructure.
咁首先我哋講一講誒背誒關於呢個金融機構處置條例嗰個背景，其實誒自二零零七年以嚟咧歐盟誒同埋歐盟嘅國家同埋美國咧都面對住好嚴重嘅金融危機，就好似誒喺九十年代嘅亞洲一樣啦。咁由於咧一般嘅清盤程序咧誒對於，
處理誒具系統重要性嘅金融機構嘅倒閉咧，其實就唔係咁適合。咁所以咧，當時誒好多嘅國家咧都係採取咗一啲前所未有嘅行動，譬如大量噉樣動用公帑去誒挽救呢一啲金融機構。咁有見及此咧，二二十個集團嘅領導。
咁誒，金融穩定理事會嘅成員地區咧，就當時承諾咗係需要咧去設立啊一套有效嘅處置機制，係根據一套叫做有效嘅金融機構處置機制主要元素去設立呢個處置機制咧，就希望可以用一啲方法咧係誒適當噉。
咁誒有關誒金融機構處置機制條例嘅誒生效日期公告咧，咁事實上啊處置條例咧誒已經喺誒二零一六年六月咧立法會已經通過咗，噉佢就係為受涵蓋嘅金融機構咧設立咗一個跨界別嘅處置機制，咁主要嘅目的就係。
希望符符合頭先所講嘅金融穩定理事會主要元素裏邊嘅國際標準標準啦，咁令到咧啊處置機制當局係有啊必須嘅權力，有有所需要嘅權力咧，係當呢啲不可持續經營但係而又具系統重要性嘅金融機構佢倒閉嘅。
咁誒，我哋建議就係誒金融機構處誒金融機構處置機制受保障安排規例，一間誒誒香誒金管局嘅同事會會簡介嗰個內容。誒通過咗呢個先誒先定立後審議嘅程序之後咧，我哋就會誒讓呢一個處置機制嘅主。
呢條文喺二零一七年七月七日生效，咁條例生效其實係誒達至到誒幾個目的嘅，就唔單止可以加強到香港金融體係嘅抵禦能力啦，亦都鞏固咗我哋作為啊全球誒國際金融中心嘅地位，亦都咧係令到我哋可以符合。
所以，Under Section 75 of the FIRA, the Secretary for Financial Services and Treasury may make regulations as subsidiary legislation to safeguard the economic effect of certain financial arrangements termed protected arrangements. In resolution, there are six types of financial arrangements identified as protected arrangement under Section 74.
of the FIRO, they include clearing and settlement system arrangements, netting arrangements, secured arrangements, set-off arrangements, structured finance arrangements and title transfer arrangements. And given these will be important throughout the rest of our session, I'll just give a brief description of each of those arrangements.
securitizations。
The risk of economic effect of protected arrangements being undermined is most likely to occur.
currents of specific events and include asset-backed securities.
所以，非常簡單，這就是財務的鋪路，通過這條路，付款是進行的，交易是結算和清結的。
Without being able to do this, capital requirements would be much larger, as they would have to be based on a gross exposure.
一淨係安排，means an arrangement under which a number of claims or obligations can be converted into a net claim or obligation.
set-off arrangement means an arrangement under which two or more debts, claims or obligations can be set off against each other.
asset-backed commercial paper, residential and commercial mortgage-backed securities, and collateralised debt obligations and covered bonds.
所以那係只係一個高層面的總覽，關於呢啲規例傾向保護和定義為保護安排。
Set-off and netting arrangements are important to financial institutions, as they allow regulatory capital requirements to be based on the net exposure under the arrangement.
這些這些規例提供確 certainty on the treatment of these arrangements, and this is important because financial market participants rely on these protections as risk mitigation tools and as sources of financing.
Our objective is not to disrupt these, and this is important to prevent contagion and wider financial instability from resolution of a participating member of a clearing and settlement system arrangement.
And finally, title transfer arrangements means an arrangement under which a person transfers assets to another person on terms provided for the other person to transfer assets if specified obligations are discharged. These include particular reverse repurchase transactions or obligations.
secured arrangements mean an arrangement under which a person acquires by way of security an actual or contingent interest in the property of another, an arrangement under which creditors seek to protect themselves against credit risk through taking charge over an asset or assets belonging to the debtor.
所以，保護安排措施規例是設計，使得RA或決議權力應行使權力，以一種方式，是保護經濟效果，的保護安排決議。最終，這創造了對決議權力使用權力的限制，就六種類型的金融安排，我剛剛描述。
structured finance arrangement，means an arrangement under which a person creates and issues an instrument，under which some or all of the returns or amount due，or the method of settlement is determined by reference to price value，or parameters，or the changes in the price value and parameters of financial assets or the occurrence of non。
Thank you.
噉。
在事件中。
好，誒，政府嗰邊仲有冇咩嘢補充啊？
誒，我想問咧，就誒，而家我哋呢個嘅規則咧。
誒有六個受保障安排啦，咁嗰個A至F。
誒就應該理論上係唔會擴大嗰個A至F嗰六個誒範圍啦。
咁誒，即係我我講意思係，譬如話誒結算啊、交易系統啊、淨額結算安排啊、抵押保證安排嗰扎啦，抵押誒抵消啊嗰啲。
The proposed approach to the PAR is largely modelled on that adopted by the United Kingdom, and that required by the European Union's Bank Recovery and Resolution Directive.
冇啦嗬，冇咁而家不如誒畀我哋嘅委員提問啦。噉啊，第一位係誒陶錦新議員，唔該。主席，我想問問咧嗰個誒而家嗰個。
and two, while at the same time, provides an appropriate degree of flexibility for the resolution authority to exercise resolution powers in order to achieve orderly resolution consistent with the resolution objectives.
在金融市場基礎設施，廣義上講，回應者普遍同意對《條例》的處理方式，提供了建設性的和一些技術性的細微意見，我們已考慮到在制定最終《條例》時。
where a partial property transfer is made by the resolution authority, or where bail-in, where liabilities are written down or converted, without taking into account linked assets or rights entitled to be set off or netted under documented agreements.
條文亦都提供適當的後果，應當在極為罕見的事件中，即 inadvertent action by the resolution authority，導致受保護安排中部分的權利、資產權利和負債被不一致地處理，與受保護安排的目標不符。
The powers provide the appropriate degree of protection for each type of protected arrangement, with specific carve-outs for certain rights and liabilities under certain arrangements designed to provide one confidence for financial market participants that critical risk mitigation and funding techniques will be protected with certainty and predictability.
On public consultation, the Financial Services and Treasury Bureau (HKMA), Insurance Authority and the SFC jointly conducted a two-month public consultation, which began in November and ended in January on the proposed approach to Protected Arrangements Regulation. We engaged with key stakeholders during the consultation period and received eleven submissions from industry, professional bodies and.
OK。
嗯。
唔會。
噉。
Thank you very much.
金融機構或者銀行係。
咁但係個問題就係，我我相信咧，你都要解釋一下咧，就係譬如話好簡單，我就存一百蚊喺銀行啫。
誒，如果我用一個誒簡單噉樣問咧，就係仲有冇一啲乜嘢嘅？
誒喺依個噉樣嘅誒處置條例裏邊咧，係嘅。
一個存款喺個銀行，噉係咪可以因為有一個誒處置之後咧，我冇曬咧噉啊？
There are some specific carve-outs which will go into more detail when I step through the regulations to the protections provided to those financial arrangements, and they are largely designed to achieve two objectives.
The way I would respond to the question is: these regulations specify a set of restrictions on the resolution authority. When they apply, there are tools in the event of a future bank failure.
喺呢個受保障安排，即係喺呢個規例之下咧，唔會係受保障安排個範圍嚟處理嘅咧。咁嗱，我即係舉一個例啊，嚇，即係用普通市民嘅普通常人嘅角度啊，例如我。
The first one，朱姐啊，朱姐，朱姐，誒，我我我希望，即係你你你你講到咁咁大嘅係啦，我我我我完，我嗰啲係之前個條例嗰度，我有行有之前有參加都學到啲嘢啦嚇，即係咁講。
由使用決議工具，這是很重要的，因為這些安排、這些財政安排提供非常重要的風險緩解保護，給金融機構，而且對於資金市場也很重要。
And by identifying the six financial arrangements which we define as protected arrangements, it provides certainty to those arrangements that on their treatment by the resolution authority in the event of a resolution. So we make clear here that those arrangements will not change or be impacted.
係咪？
歧視嗰啲有錢人。
要要要重組或者處置啦。
嗱，如果你唔係噉嘅話咧，
噉佢咧就誒，就係。
最後咧，我存嗰百蚊係冇月冇咗嘅。
噉我成個香港咧就保唔住啦，咁即係金融體係。
因為係喺某一次嘅大波浪裏邊，就係。
我哋而家嗰啲保障存款係幾多錢啊？去到五十萬，啊五十萬啦，OK。
嗱，你明白咧？即係譬如我我我又我我唔係話即係叫做咩啊？誒。
嗱，咁當然啦，你你可能話：如果我唔係有呢個機制，連你嗰五十萬都取消曬。
即係我舉例，譬如話，如果你話畀我聽，我呢個例咧就係唔會影響。
總之，你有五十萬或以下嘅存款咧，呢個機制不適用於取消你嗰五十萬嘅存款。
不過就我你明白咧，因為始終咧，即係個社會咧係由個masses係最大多數係唔係咁有錢嘅人啊組成啦。
誒 consequence after the regime has been taken in effect。我我舉個例，我更加希望誒就是各各方面諗啦。嗱，我舉例啫。
咁啦，Mr. Wright，呃，Would you please，呃，you know，呃，reply exactly to the concrete queries raised by Mr. Toll? He would like to know， um， you know， to quote the example about the deposit owned by any customer of a bank. So please give him， you know， the。
咁到嗰陣時咧，就大家唔上銀行啦。
擺入去咯，於是我就會。
誒，或或，或者，或者咁講啦。
因為你依個例咧，就令到佢唔相信銀行。
擺定卅萬喺屋企啊，大佬！我最多信你廿萬啦，我冇做，我做緊養生啊噉樣。
我諗下，究竟個市民諗緊，我係咪將我？
但係個問題咧，即係如果你有啲嘢唔係有絕對嘅exception嘅咧，噉我我諗下。
即係即係變咗，我我我個諗法咧就你你係我我明白你嗰係一個大嘅整體嘅誒利益啊！
我覺得家家地都幾廿萬人選出嚟啊！我都要立同為佢哋諗下，喂，佢哋最多絕大多數係窮嘅人嚟嘅。如果我以後，
你你你可以噉樣講啦，不過咧，即係我真係要好認真，當你喺呢兩個稱嘅時候，即係如果你冇呢個例外咧。
嗱，佢佢我舉個例子，譬如譬如話，因因為因為我如果積五十萬喺銀行，咁不如唔好啦，我隨時雖然我都有啲誒道氏風險啊嗰啲啦嚇，噉我話老虎蟹都。
保險箱費啦，係嘛？咁到時起碼我開翻嘅時候啦，係嘛？就就就唔會net咗啊嘛，net即係抵消咗啊嘛，係嘛？即係個behaviour會轉嘅，我希望你明白。尤其是係大風浪，即係我我哋講嘅時候，咁希望你即係喺用呢個角度，可唔可以解解呢個謠言咧？噉樣。
嘅時候咧，呢個功能咧係會完全噉樣去誒轉讓過去嘅，即係唔會因為誒我哋去處置呢個金融機構咧，令到啲存款係攞唔到誒嗰個存款嘅。咁或者我請啊Mr White誒再詳細講一講嗰個技嗰個技術嗰個嘅意見，即係呢個規則裏面邊一條？
點都擺定，我咩都好咧，就揾個方方法噉啊！嗱，起碼我知道咧，safety box box真係冇嘅呢度嚇冇netting嘅。噉就講講，我哋換曬錢就擠曬落去嗰個保險箱嗰度啦。即係譬如匯豐，我擠匯豐匯豐，點都擠幾百萬落去。大佬，我寧願畀你個個年年又又一千蚊咩？
主席或者我哋講下個嘢先。其實條例誒本身個其中嘅目的咧誒就係話要保障銀行一啲好啊關鍵嘅金融功能，其中一個就係包括存款。咁其實喺我哋誒制定呢個受保障安排規例裏邊咧，其實我哋都係特別誒對存款咧係。
有一個誒誒嘅嘅處理嘅方法，但係至於嗰個即係嗰個技術係誒係點，我依家請金管局嘅同事解解就係其實誒，我哋就係希望呢一個關即係一個好重要嘅存款嘅功能咧，係唔會受影響嘅，即係嗰啲存款係會咧，如果係啊轉讓咗去啊畀一個買家。
啊，OK。
所以那筆金額是完全保證的。
用半版紙嘅啫，你下一次你你再擺埋呢個。
個咧可以喺會議之後，你哋再follow啊，好唔好啊？Mr. Wright，please。
咁但係咧，誒個問題就係，因為如果佢係銀行咧。
在這補助立法，我會提供那澄清和寫作之後。
deposits are protected up to the deposit protection scheme limit, which is five hundred thousand.
然後突然間咧，佢因為要有要，你可能做一個vehicle啊，就去接管咗呢個啊啊銀行呢個存款，就保障翻個存款啦噉樣。
嘅，我哋呢個委員會啊嘅文件裏邊，即係我問我如此問過呢個問題，你如此答過呢個問題，OK，噉你就指出，譬如啊，或者我哋法律顧問都去幫手睇睇啊，係嘛，就係條例第幾條？
所以如果我們會轉移存款到橋銀或到私營部門買家，因此存款人會繼續有權使用他們的存款資金。這就是決議案的主要目標。在巴林。
So under the FIRL, the primary legislation, deposits are protected. The primary objective of a resolution, whether it's a transfer or a bail-in, is to ensure continuity in access to the deposits.
另一個技術嘅問題，最後啦，主席，我問埋呢個同我走嘅，唔好意思，因為有唔緊要，就係嗰個嗱，你話舉個例啦，譬如喺大風大浪嘅時候，噉你咪轉啦，噉你轉咗都保障啦。舉個例，如果突然間，譬如你你有一個問題，就係有間銀行，噉我存咗喺銀行啦嚇，OK。
主席，誒，你可唔可以指出喺誒受保障安排規例裏邊邊一條係有呢樣？即係等我有咩事同我啲選民交代啊，嗱呢條啊嗱噉樣。明白。噉你指出嚟得唔得？係啦，Mr. Right，誒，我諗啊，阿陶委員嘅意思咧係呢一個誒處置機制裏邊有冇一啲？
誒條款好明確講，佢就唔會影響其他嘅一啲誒，即係誒客户擁有嘅權利。不而佢exclude咗from誒其他嘅，譬如存款保障計劃裏邊啲嘢係不受影響。佢有冇一條誒好明確嘅條款去聲明呢一樣嘢？如果可以咧，主席咧，你你不如。
指出規例第幾條指出，as how就係保障咗乜乜啦，咁OK，噉就變咗咧五十萬以下咧，總言之咧就我就唔使叫佢咧啲市民咧就話，因為有咗儲值條例咧，你就不如換幾廿萬現金咧就擺喺你保險箱啦，即係我寧願你啊噉樣。噉啊，或者阿Mr. Wright你先解釋一下，噉我諗書面嗰個。
Sure. So the protections are provided for in the Financial Institutions Resolution Ordinance, the primary legislation under Part 4 or Part 1, Section 11, that specifies the protection provided to deposits. So it's more in the primary legislation which is and not specified.
再另一個波浪咧。
點知突然間嗰間公司？
一個月後就冇咗啦。
就五十萬，就喺嗰間公司。O.K.
但係突然間，因為處置之後咧，就去咗個唔係銀行。
而嗰間公司咧，暫時咧就係佢唔係銀行嚟嘅。
圖委員嘅意思咧，就係如果一間銀行出現問題。
噉就誒，我就會根據嗰個存款保障條例咧，我就會有得保嘅，因為佢有一個機制。
O.K.冧咗，亦都亦都呢啲所有處置唔到啦。O.K.即係已經處置唔到啦。好啦。
好啦，突然間，大家嚟試下，我諗起一樣嘢就係，你根據呢個規例，根據呢個咧，你就係轉咗一間公司。
但係你跟住呢度咧搞亂咗嘅，OK喺嗰度嘅。之前我其實有個錢咧，就係唔係存款，而係一個欠我一個債。
噉我話慘啦！噉我本來第一次第一浸咧，第一浪咧，我就係有存款保障嗰度，因為佢係銀行。O.K.
即係有可能嘅，但係因為你你你臨時啊嘛，頂住先嘛，大佬係咪？你唔好唔好唔好搞住啦噉樣。O K，咁嗰個就唔係銀行，唔係銀行咧，一齣咗嗰個範圍咧，死啦！
而而我就因為你處理緊咧，我可能根本咧就係你誒moratorium，即係你唔能夠即刻攞錢嘅，唔出奇，即係好大浪嘅時候嚇噉，我明嘅。但係慘啊！慘在咧，跟住一個月後咧，另一波嚟咧，我就冇買啦，因為連嗰個存款保障都冇啦嘛，因為你只係一間公司接管食咗間銀行嗰個存款，我變咗一個集。
而家個債咧，佢都冧埋啦，咁咪冇咯。Ordinary creditors變咗，會唔會有噉嘅情況？同埋，如果得嘅咧，你亦都幫我誒半板子解一解，同埋呢度點樣有有冇咩原機可以令到係保障得到嘅咧？噉樣我我理解誒誒金管嗰個同事啊，即係話啊啊。
就要啟動呢個金融處置機制。咁呢啲資產，嗰啲存款啊，或者負債咧，就轉到一間無論係過渡機構啦，可以係資產管理公司啦，或者一間暫有嘅公有公司啦。咁轉咗之後，如果再出現另一波嘅危機，會唔會嗰啲過渡機構、資產管理公司或者暫有嘅公有？
主席，我個問題唔係嗰度。
correct and one further point.
或者用consequential amendment去問嗰個存款保障條例嗰邊。
The bridge institution would be an authorised institution. It would be a bank.
就算你依度誒話誒，正如主席都講咧，佢一間過渡公司。
The same points would apply to the temporary public institution, public owned institution.
任何 deposit that would be in the bridge institution would have the same protections that it always had under the deposit protection scheme.
Great. So I'll try to address that in a couple of simple statements. The transfer of the deposits to a bridge institution.
And it would have to comply with all the same statutory and regulatory obligations as an authorised institution, as regulated by the HKMA.
And it would then be the responsibility of the authorities to ensure that the firm was always in compliance with those minimum conditions for authorisation.
The bridge institution and the temporary public company would need to comply with minimum conditions for authorisation, including capital and funding requirements.
會唔會嘅意思就係話，無論轉畀邊個過渡機構咧，所有用乜嘢形式出現嘅過渡機構咧，都仍然會係視作一間誒authorised institution嘅。
就話去延伸埋嗰間公司，誒少咗一家銀行。我我我舉例。係啦，睇下金管局嘅解釋，即係已經喺誒而家嘅條例裏邊有冇作出呢個考慮先啦，好唔好啊？我哋聽下誒Miss Wright嘅解釋嚇，唔該曬Miss Wright。
誒，但係Mr. Wright誒喺啊文件第六段嘅E嗰度都講咧，亦都可以容許轉讓畀一間叫暫時嘅公有公司。咁嗰間暫時嘅公有公司會唔會都係誒當做一間All-Private Institution咧？
即係誒會後咧，亦都好似頭先第一條問題噉，有一個書面嘅回覆，即係立紙傳召啦，可以咁講嚇。咁誒，或者請金管局嘅同事先。我問問一句就係：，好有咧，如果需要你喺呢度唔足夠保障到咧，你可能咧就要用嗰個，你考慮喺呢度。
有公司會出現倒閉嘅危機，而令到咧，本來覺得已經係受咗一啲保障，變成咧，因為嗰間已經唔係金融機構啦。咁會唔會呢個條例都延伸到去，令到有一啲保障咧？咁呢呢個係誒阿陶陶委員想問嘅問題。同埋，除咗今日口頭答覆之外咧，佢希望。
認為。
存款保障條例。
要佢。
Mr. Wright有冇補充？
但Whether，according，to，that，deposit。
F.I.O. to be a authorized institution.
所以我會just重複一下， deposit protection seen protection。
噉你可能你話我我哋誒過路公司嗰個要求咧都要同一間銀行啊，所有嗰啲要求一樣啦。但係我而家唔係講呢樣，我講緊咧就係。
都會延伸個保障去嗰度，可能你改嘅咧就唔喺呢一度，而係改嗰個存款保障條例嗰度，最追到去另一個我存款轉咗嗰間公司嗰度。
而引申嘅金融機構都喺埋裏邊咧，噉我諗個意思係噉啊嘛。
你轉咗落去嗰間過渡公司咧，係由呢個存款保障條例係會嗰個，因為係存款，而嗰個當作存款，而嗰個公司就算佢個未唔嗰秒鐘唔係一個有銀行執照嘅，根據存款保障條例。
如果冇咧，我請你考慮。嗱，當然咧，你你依個有個gap都唔定嘅，可能你而家你你過到呢個，你即刻要攞一條例做都唔定嘅。嚇，但係咧呢個point咧，我希望你即係因為好technical嘅，好技術性，我希望我哋法律顧問或者你法律顧問咧，用法律角度嚟答，好嘛？OK，好。
for deposits of a failed bank that was transferred to a bridge institution or a temporary public ownership company, would still benefit from the same protection of the deposit protection scheme。或或者我我同我代阿陶委陶委員再問清楚嘅意思係咁嗱。頭先好清楚啦，所有嘅過渡機構咧都會視為一間AI，但係我諗阿陶委員嘅意。
見咧係誒，如果嗰個存款保障計劃裏邊因應呢個金融儲置機制咧，佢有冇一個條款已經令到咧金融儲置機制下邊產生嘅一啲隱身嘅金融機構都喺嗰個存款保障計劃裏邊咧係已經cover咗。我諗佢嘅意思係噉，所以咧呢個就我唔知啊。
你如果好熟嗰個存款保障條例嘅，可能你即刻答到啦。如果唔係嘅，我諗阿陶偉榮員嘅意見就話，會唔會都誒誒攞一個機會去再重新檢視下存款保障機嘅機制裏邊咧嗰個誒金融機構嘅定義係咪都包埋一旦產生金融處置嘅情況咧誒？
by which the deposit protection scheme scheme ordinance can chase or can follow or deem that the new temporary institution, although may be deemed by this ordinance.
sorry，little bit clumsy。
保險方面啊，阿Tony有冇咩講法？保險界點睇？
誒阿阿陶委員，啊而家係阿陳建波委員嚇，唔該曬。
接受啊！特別係保險公司提出嘅，有冇啲邊咩嘢你唔接受，而你哋會點樣做咧？可唔可以解解啊？
我諗好清楚啦，杜委員嘅意見。誒，我諗就呢個係要會後再去大家跟進一下嘅。唔該曬。
保護條例會 deem那新AI under this F.I.R.O. 會 be an AI under that ordinance.
邊位回答係又係啊，Mr. Wright？嗯，我會pass over to my insurance sector colleague in a second to offer any additional points， but I think。
睇一睇嗰個誒二零一七年金融機構處置機制條例生效日期嘅公告。咁誒，其實誒呢個公告咧就係啊由啊財經事務及副務局局長咧就指定咗二零一七年七月七日咧就係啊處置條例。
So, for example, as a result of the consultation feedback, we've refined our definition of financial contracts, and we've provided more examples of the to accompany our description of clearing and settlement systems. But very much in this refining feedback.
份文件咧，其實都影響銀行同保險公司啦。噉就你哋有個諮詢總結嘅嚇，又做咗係六月四號啦嚇，誒四月六號啦。噉啊有十一份嘅嘅意見，我想了解咧，即係嗱，如果你誒同意咗處理咗或者修訂咗，我冇問題啦。我想問一問有冇邊一樣咧係你哋不？
As set out in the presentation, industry was broadly supportive of our approach to protected arrangements, and the nature of the comments that we received as part of the consultation feedback were largely around clarifying definitions and clarifying the scope of the protections provided to the arrangements that we've.
誒係呢一呢一個噉嘅arrangement嗰度咧，主要都係一啲金融工具啲誒嗰個保障之下嗰啲噉嘅喺保險界嗰方面咧，就冇咩特別嘅意見喺度再再發表噉。我想再問咧，即係你公佈咗呢個諮詢總結之後咧，有冇新嘅誒查詢咧？無論係銀行或者係insurance，好啦，唔該，記者長，即係基本上。
上你覺得係第一句瞭解啦，冇反對意見啦，執行上亦都冇困難嘅，係咪？你可唔可以有噉嘅結論？誒，可以噉樣結論。O K，好啊。噉我冇冇嘢問啦，主席。好誒，噉我順便喺度問啦。如果大家冇問題咧，誒，仲需唔需要做誒一個即係誒邀請全體嚟再諮詢咧？
我諗不需要啦，因為我正如我講咗，都冇業界冇乜其他意見。好，誒噉我個人都唔需要嘅，咁誒我諗秘書處嗰邊可以誒登記翻。咁跟住落嚟，我諗係時間，我哋不如逐條誒過一個個法例嘅誒條文，好唔好啊？誒邊位負責啊？請問秘書長。誒首先。
誒嗰個生效公告咧，誒咁誒，我呢邊會誒介紹一下嗰個cross嘅咁誒嗰個逐逐項審議，跟住輪到誒受保障安排規例咧，就會由金管局嘅同事去介紹誒逐項介紹嘅。好啊，唔該誒，咁請啊，秘書長你先開始第一部分啦。好啊，多謝主席。咁首先誒，就係我哋。
主要條文嘅生效日期噉啊，其實仲有啊三部分條文係仲未實施嘅噉，分別就係第八部第誒一一四一四四至一四八條噉就係有關誒退購報報酬嘅事宜咁誒。第二誒方面咧就係第一九二條，係就係關於咧。
propose to be the seventh of July.
冇冇噉，我哋誒，不如開始第二部分嘅簡介，好唔好啊？唔該啊，Mr. Right。
啊！向處置機制當局發出關於提出清盤呈請意向通知嘅條文。
清本請請相關嘅法庭程序咧，先至生效嘅。咁而啊，第十五步。
exclusions from certain protections under the regulation to ensure that the resolution authority has the appropriate degree of flexibility to secure an orderly resolution in the event of FI failure.
pursuant to section 31(1) of the Interpretation and General Clauses Ordinance, expressions used in the regulation have the same meaning as in the ordinance conferring the power, i.e. the FIRO.
The coming into operation of the regulation is tied specifically to Part Five of the FiR, as Part Five provides for the operative powers, the stabilisation options, bail-in, transfer, etc., in respect of which Par establishes the appropriate constraints on the resolution authority.
七月七日咧係較為先嘅，咁所以咧就係冇必要咧係誒將佢生效嘅。咁誒我嘅誒簡介關於個生效公告誒就係咁多，多謝主席。誒，先睇下各位委員有冇喺呢方面有問題先。冇。
啲噉，我哋亦都係誒諮詢過司法機構政務處之後咧，都係認為啊呢一條咧最好就係喺中審法院首席法官誒根據第一九二括弧三條訂立咗規則誒規管咗關於呢一個誒。
而第十五部、第十分部，即係第二二百至二三二條咧，就係啊有關對二零一五年保險公司修訂條例嘅相應修訂。噉啊，第八部係關於退購事宜嘅咧，就啊，我哋係經過啊諮詢司法機構、政務處。
之後咧，咁誒，我哋希望可以呢一部分係誒喺中審法院首席法官根據第一四五括弧八條訂立咗規則啊，去規管誒點樣去提出誒申請退購令嘅相關原原眾法庭實務同埋程序之後咧，先至生效。
嘅噉，至於第一九二條咧，就定明咗，除非嗰個呈請人已經向處置機制當局發出書面通知，否則咧就係唔可以向原眾法庭提出呈請，要求咧去清盤受涵蓋嘅金融機構或者佢嘅控權公司。
誒第十分部即係二二八至二三二條咧，就係對二零一五年保險公司修訂條例作出修訂。誒而有關修訂咧，因為只係喺處置條例畀誒呢個保險公司修訂條例嘅第二階段條文，即係關於。
咧啊！獨立保險業監管局取代而家保險業監理處嘅監管職能。如果我哋係早過佢之下咧，先至需要採用嘅。咁但係而家咧，由於嗰個保險公司嘅修訂條例咧，會喺二零一七年六月二十六日生效，就畀我哋處置條例嘅。
我會走過每一個節目。的條例來解釋它是如何運作的。第1部分規定條例的開始和解釋定義的術語。第1節規定條例在指定的日期生效，即第5部分生效，如先前所討論的。
permitted by the empowering provisions in the FIRON.
和security interest under the arrangement clearly linked to those assets.
Section 4.1 provides a definition of protected structured finance arrangement.
making clear that the definition covers securitizations whether established through a true sale or synthetically.
政策目標，這裡是預防決議行動從打斷支付、結算和清算的運作。
Section four two establishes that any role of originator in a true sale securitisation is to be treated as a liability formed, forming part of a protected structured finance arrangement.
This means that to be recognised as a protected structured finance arrangement, the pool of assets backing the notes issued under the synthetic security must be clearly identifiable.
section three four clarifies that for a synthetic securitisation, a security interest is only to be treated as part of the arrangement if it is attached to a specific and sufficiently identifiable asset.
listed in section three, one of those protected by the insolvency override in section twenty one and forty five one of the PSS VFO and the SFO respectively.
The objective here is to make sure that key roles that an entity in resolution plays in securitisation, beyond simply the underlying assets and notes issued against them, are covered by the definition, so that they should not be split apart by a resolution authority in the event of FI failure.
Section 3.2 provides for the interpretation of a number of terms used in the definition of specified arrangements above in Section 3.1 by reference to defined terms in the SFO or the PSSVFO. This is necessary because these terms are defined separately in the SFO and PSSVFO.
This broad description is designed to capture arrangements created through real or synthetic transfer of assets, such that assets operate as security against notes issued to investors from securitisation vehicles. For example, asset-backed securities, asset-backed commercial paper, mortgage-backed securities.
section two sets out specific definitions used only in the regulation, certain of which can only be properly considered in the context of the relevant provisions of the regulation, in which they are used, namely financial activity, financial contracts and transferable securities. The primary use of these definitions is in the context of defining appropriate.
The two more substantive definitions in Section 2 are of protected clearing and settlement system arrangements and protected structured finance arrangements, which make reference to Section 3 and Section 4 respectively. These definitions specify the classes of clearing and settlement system arrangements and structured finance arrangements to which this regulation applies, as
Protected clearing and settlement arrangements is defined in section 3.1. The definition covers certain specified arrangements that are governed by the rules and directions relating to participation in the clearing and settlement of transactions within a designated clearing and settlement system or a recognised clearinghouse. The specified arrangements.
section 44 further provides that in the case of both true sale and synthetic securitizations, agreements constituting a securitisation structure covering mutual relationship between the key players in the structure, e.g. for example the originator and the issuer, trustees and the servicers for those vehicles, are to be treated as forming part of the protect.
for the purposes of banking capital rules.
減緩風險，和降低資本成本。
under that arrangement, not just some of them.
And this avoids the disproportionate constraint on the use of resolution tools.
by separating out the failed institutions, critical financial functions sufficiently quickly and decisively.
安排，捕獲such clauses would severely restrict a resolution authority's ability to achieve orderly resolution.
受託人或抵押服務商， are covered by the definition to ensure that those services continue in resolution.
Section 51A establishes that set-off and netting or title transfer arrangements must be documented, or otherwise evidenced in writing.
section 5.1b clarifies that either the transferor or person under the arrangement is entitled to set off or net for the arrangements to qualify for treatment under section 5.1.
第一，轉移契約；第二，物權轉移契約；第三，擔保契約。第二部分則是關於決議權限在物權轉移契約中的作用。
Part two of the regulation establishes what a resolution authority is to seek to do when making a regulated Part Five instrument that transfers assets, rights or liabilities as appropriate to the specific arrangement that are or form part of different types of protected arrangements.
Section 5.1c reflects the policy intention that clauses entitling a non-defaulting party to make no or only limited payments, even where the defaulting party is a net creditor, are not afforded protection, given that such clauses are not regarded as valid bilateral netting arrangements agreements.
structured finance arrangement, if those relationships are directly linked to the relative underlying assets or payments to be made from their proceeds to noteholders, the objective here is to make sure that the key roles that an entity in resolution plays in a protected structured finance arrangement, for example as a swap provider or as
And just briefly to recap, a Part Five instrument is defined in Section 74 of the PAr as resulting in partial property transfer being effected, or contains a bail-in provision. A Part Five instrument is defined in Section 2 of the FiRo as any of as any of the following: first, a security
所以，在那部分，第5.1節規定，當一個決議權力機構在制定《規管第5條》法規時，轉移了屬於部分抵銷安排、淨值安排或物權轉移安排的權利或負債，當中涉及轉移人和某個人時，該決議權力機構應盡力將所有權利和負債轉移給該人。
The policy objective is to provide certainty that important set-off and netting rights are afforded an appropriate degree of protection in resolution, by preventing a resolution authority from cherry-picking favourable contracts under such an arrangement. Given that set-off and netting are relied upon by financial institutions and their counterparties to
Section five one D provides that the rights and liabilities under five one must first arise out of the arrangement. That is, they must not arise from broad set off clauses that extend to any or all relationship between a counterparty and the financial institution, rather than those specific to the.
rights and liabilities relating to subordinated debt.
second， not be excluded under section five two。
rights and liabilities relating to transferable securities as defined in section two.
轉移，和的，利益，的，證券，應，不，應，轉移，，，，除非，負債，也，轉移，，，，和，反之，亦，然。
The undertake of critical financial functions, for example, deposits, can be transferred to support the continuity of access to those operations.
這反映他們在債權人階層，和政策目標是確保損失被吸收在決議，consistent with how they would have been in a liquidation.
And finally, rights and liabilities arising in connection with the undertaking of financial activities relating to the claims for damages, and award of damages or a claim under an indemnity.
或那它可留下在一個殘餘實體，來吸收損失，作為適當，例子，包括次級債務或可轉讓的擔保，，無關乎任何與抵銷或淨值的權利。
這些權利和義務如下：權利和義務關聯到存款與轉讓人；權利和義務關聯到資產，以收據為形式，向轉讓人由存款人。
The rights and liabilities under Section 52 are intended to be those that a resolution authority would need a high degree of certainty that it could transfer quickly and decisively to secure the continuity of critical financial functions, for example, deposits.
the that the the exclusions for subordinated debt and transferable securities are to provide that equity, junior debt and unsecured debt liabilities can be left behind in a residual entity to absorb the losses that caused the FI's failure.
recognising the need for these specific carve-outs, it does not impact the no creditor worse off in liquidation compensation protections that still are available to all pre-resolution shareholders and creditors. So that's just important to bear that in mind.
Moving on to section E, rights and liabilities arising under a contract entered into by or on behalf of the transferor, otherwise than in the course of undertaking financial activity, which is defined in section two. This exclusion is to provide flexibility to the resolution authority, such that operating liabilities relating to
Section 6.1 provides that a resolution authority, in making a regulated Part 5 instrument, transferring any constituent part of a secured arrangement, is to transfer the arrangement together in entirety. This means that assets and rights under a secured arrangement should only be transferred to if the liability and benefit of the security are all.
Mr. Wright, may I suggest you know because I suppose all our members has thoroughly review all the detailed terms and conditions of the proposed bill. So you you might you know introduce the detailed content by section. That means you you you shouldn't.
或你 need not to read out all the detail provisions there on. Instead, you can give us a heads up on each particular section instead, so that we can you know raise questions even when we we think appropriate. Okay, thank you, thank you, Mr. Wright. I'll go a little bit more quickly.
所以。
This is one of the specified carve-outs.
幫助進一步反映諮詢回饋，我們收到的，和釐清我們在規例中使用的定義。
所以，moving on，Part three of the regulation establishes what a resolution authority is to seek to not to do when applying bail-in stabilisation option.
係。
foreign court were to restrict the transfer of that foreign property, so the the key point here is that over time by engaging with foreign authorities, we would hope that the risk of such action by a foreign court would be reduced.
Section 10, 11 and 12 establish the consequences, however unlikely, should a resolution authority inadvertently act in a manner inconsistent with the objectives of Part 2.
要被恢復，如果有任何不當行為，無論是透過補償、補償或反轉移動資產或負債，第12條最後規定，讓受讓方可以否認，到達某個程度，會破壞清算和結算系統安排。
Section two provides that the resolution authority, irrespective of whether the secured arrangement is established using a fixed or floating charge, that also is that provided for under the protection. Section six three provides that the resolution authority is required, under section one, does not apply where purported secured arrangement.
has been made in contravention of any legal restrictions. So this under the banking ordinance. So that's another important point to bear in mind. Section 7.1 provides that in making a Part Five instrument which transfers assets and liabilities, protects the structured finance arrangements. Section 7.2.
Provides that deposit liabilities of an entity in resolution that are part of a protected structured finance arrangement are not subject to what a resolutionary is required to do under section 7. So this means that the resolution authority can transfer any deposit liabilities separate from the secured arrangements.
Section eight one provides that defines the protection for clearing and settlement system arrangements. The main point here is that everything needs to be transferred together, or everything needs to be left behind together. Section eight two then sets out a list of non-exhaustive examples to.
Section nine establishes the where a regulated Part Five instrument purports to transfer foreign property that is set off part of a set off netting and title transfer or secured or protected structured finance arrangement, the resolution authority has not acted inconsistent with the objectives of the Part if.
作為我提到在概覽演講中，雖然考慮到必須提供在事件發生時的後果，當決議機構採取誤導行動時，我們認為提供給決議機構的決議規劃權限，在啟動法羅羣島後會減少誤導行動的風險。
And also, as we engage with financial institutions as part of resolution planning, the development of by those institutions of information systems capable of identifying protected arrangements quickly and with a high degree of certainty will also reduce further reduce the risk of any unintended inadvertent action that results in the.
嗯。
before they can be subject to bailen.
And examples of these liabilities are as follows.
on which losses would be expected to be imposed in a bail-in execution.
一-liability owed in relation to subordinated debt issued by the affected entity.
一連係應付，係應付。
一-liability owed in relation to unsecured debt instruments, an unsecured liability in relation to any instrument or contract.
With a residual maturity period of 12 months or more at the point of issuance, and that is not a financial contract.
Section 13.1 sets out the definitions specific to this part. I refer back to these as part of the relevant operative provisions.
This is consistent with sort of the general feedback we receive from industry, particularly in the context of derivatives. So this is a very important provision for orderly bail-in, and as it applies to these contracts.
Briefly, section 13 to list the liabilities excluded from the definition of protected liabilities. Section 133 clarifies, for the purpose of the definition of protected liabilities, that an arrangement that can be permitted to set off a netting.
Moving on under under Part E, not does this this definition of liabilities is not excluded by Section 2. So this is the liability under Section 2. Are those liabilities that it is considered will represent good forms of loss-absorbing capacity?
With more than one counterparty, and that it does not matter whether the rights to set off are net is only exercisable under the occurrence of a particular event. So, section 133 explains how a liability is to be treated as if it had been converted into net debt, claim or obligation, which is relevant for the purposes of this section.
Section 14 is an important section as provides that the resolution authority is to seek not to make bailing provisions in respect of a protected liability, and it spells out the definition for protected liability in section 13.1 as a liability that a is owed to a third party.
Under section 10, it provides the rights of a person to set off a netting, where a transfer under a set off netting entitled transfer arrangement is not affected by action taken by the resolution authority that is inconsistent with what a resolution authority was required to seek to do. Section 11 provides for an affected party's position under a secured arrangement or under a protected structured finance arrangement.
A. By infected party, B. The third party or the entity are entitled to set off and net under a set off netting entitled transfer arrangement. C. If related to the financial contract, has not been converted to a net debt or claim or obligation. And D. If related to
contract of any kind has not been converted or treated as if it had been converted into a net debtor claim. C and D ensure that financial contracts falling within the definition of in Schedule One must be converted per the terms of the relevant set-off, netting or title transfer arrangement into a net position.
And importantly, over time.
And again, just to repeat.
Section 14(2) provides.
That notwithstanding, a liability being protected.
與《The Objective》 of Section fourteen one.
and an unsecured liability owed to the group company of the affected entity.
claim or obligation or an estimate thereof, such that it can be subject to bail and consistent.
要取 steps to transfer to the affected party a required sum, as defined in Section 13.1.
Section 158 to 1511 imposed time limitations on the resolution authority, as part of the consequences.
The no creditor worse off in liquidation protections still apply to pre-resolution shareholders and creditors as part of executing the bail-in resolution.
一-liability in relation to a deposit that is not excluded from the bail-in pursuant to section 2B and C of section five, residual five of FIrO, and finally a liability in relation to a claim for damages.
一 liability, a resolution authority is not prevented from exercising bail-in provisions, pursuant to section 58C, 3C, of FIRROM, to convert, or in connection with converting, the protected liability into a net debt.
作為本地負擔能力要求的發展和設定，這應該減少對淨負債作為充足負擔能力來源的依賴。
Exactly how the required sum is to be transferred depends on whether bail-in has been effected in conjunction with a bridge, with a bridge bank, but ultimately requires a resolution authority to take action to provide shares or a payment by the relevant entity of an amount equal to the required sum.
It is however recognised that the authorities by the authorities that closing out such positions quickly, at the point of failure, may have material valuation and continuity complexities, and therefore decisions on whether to close out such provisions would be made on a case by case basis.
Section 15 establishes again consequences should a resolution authority inadvertently act in a manner inconsistent with what is required to seek not to do in section 14.1. In short, in the event that a resolution authority inadvertently makes bail-in provisions in respect of a protected liability, it must seek.
Thank you.
係啊，係。
嘅輸血，我哋使唔使延展個時間？
Setting entitlement transfer arrangements in a partial transfer.
誒，如果各位委員長冇咩其他補充？
冇啊，冇咁今日個會議就到呢度為止啦，係嘛？好，唔該曬，多謝各位嚇，唔該。
唔該曬，Mr. Wright。誒，各位委員有冇對頭先誒具體嘅條文有咩問題？冇。
四，-liabilities excluded from the definition of protected liabilities in the context of a bail-in. These contracts are securities contracts, commodities contracts, derivative contracts, and contracts for purchase, sale or delivery of currency and master agreements, so far as they relate to any of these contracts.
冇咧，噉就誒，因為咧我哋仲有一啲誒跟進事項嘅，噉我想問下誒，頭先有委員提出嘅誒要求有兩個誒書面後補嘅答覆咧，政府當局估計咧，大約要幾耐時間可以誒準備好相關嘅書面答覆啊？
嚟咧就係六月二十八號，咁所以我都會誒喺呢個誒內務委員會嗰度誒動議，係啦喺大會六月七號嘅大會度咧動議要做一個延展，咁等我哋有時間咧處理我哋頭先講嘅誒一啲書面補充啦，同埋睇下我哋有冇需要即係開第二次嘅會議，好冇啊？
和最後，如我早前所提，議程一列出了金融合約的名單，用於第一，定義金融活動；第二，定義保護的負債；第三，排除於第52條下的權利和負債，以達成有關沖銷的目標。
Do you think we can reply within? Yes, 我我哋相信一個禮拜之內，我哋應該可以回覆到秘書處。好，咁誒，如果我當日收到嗰個書面答覆咧，我哋會誒傳畀所有嘅委員閲啦。咁另外咧就誒睇完之後，我哋會盡快定下一次嘅會議日期。咁因為今日就。
已經具體嘅條文審議咗啦。我諗下次主要係睇對個書面答覆咧，大家仲有冇跟進或者因應個書面答覆咧，需唔需要做一啲對條文嘅修訂？咁誒啊，阿阿陳建波委員，啊，主席，我諗全月咧，如果冇就唔使開咯，係嘛？係咯，我睇下大家嘅意見係點啦，好冇？誒，仲有冇咩補充？
好啊，好啊。誒，我講一講嗰個時間表啊。咁個審議嘅屆滿日期咧，就誒，如果係六月十四號審議完成咧，噉我哋向內務委員會報告嘅日期咧，就應該係六月二號嘅。咁個法例嘅預告期限就六月七號。噉我睇嚟，因為要一個禮拜。
去做好呢件事咧，咁可能誒都係要延展㗎啦。咁即係話審議嘅屆滿日期咧，我哋就用二零一七年七月五號呢個誒時間段啦。咁向內務委員會報告嘅日期咧，就會相應係誒六月二十三號。咁誒動議呢個附屬法例作出嘅預告限期。